the purpose of the Panama Canal
巴拿马运河的目的
is pretty easy to understand
很容易理解
it turns a journey of this into this
它把这段旅程变成了这样
it brings the US West Coast closer to Europe
它使美国西海岸更接近欧洲
and it brings the US East Coast closer to Asia
它使美国东海岸更接近亚洲
these rather short 180 foot or
这些相当短的180英尺或
55 meter wide trenches are combined
55米宽的战壕组合在一起
perhaps the single most important
也许是最重要的
and most influential waterway
和最有影响力的水道
on earth
在地球上
that's because the entire shipping industry worldwide
那是因为全世界的航运业
is shaped by the Panama Canal
是由巴拿马运河塑造的
hundreds of years ago
几百年前
the opportunity of a canal
运河的机会
across the narrow country of Panama
横跨狭窄的巴拿马
was identified
被识别
after a few earlier false starts
在之前的几次错误开始之后
the Americans went down to Panama in 1903
美国人在1903年下到巴拿马
signed a fairly dubious treaty granting them land
签署了一个相当可疑的条约授予他们土地
dammed up a river to make an artificial lake
筑坝造人工湖
dug a trench from that lake to the Pacific
挖了一条从那个湖到太平洋的战壕
dug a trench from that lake to the Atlantic
挖了一条从湖里到大西洋的战壕
and 13 billion dollars
130亿美元
and 5600 worker fatalities later
5600名工人死亡
the canal was done
运河修好了
it officially opened the Pacific to the Atlantic
它正式打开了太平洋到大西洋的大门
on August 15 1914
1914年8月15日
as the first commercial ship the SSN con sailed through
作为SSN的第一艘商船驶过
now the Panama Canal is not just one straight shot
现在巴拿马运河不仅仅是一条直线
from ocean to ocean
从海洋到海洋
that's because the artificial lake they created
那是因为他们创造的人工湖
Gatun Lake is 85 feet or 26 meters above sea level
加屯湖海拔85英尺或26米
so cargo ships
所以货船
which can weigh more than 1 billion pounds
重量超过10亿磅
need to get up those 85 feet or
需要爬上那85英尺或者
26 meters and then back down again
26米然后再往回倒
to transit from ocean to ocean
从一个海洋到另一个海洋
like most canals to do this the Panama Canal uses locks
像大多数运河一样，巴拿马运河也使用水闸。
from the Atlantic side for example
例如，从大西洋一侧
a ship will be pulled into the first lock
一艘船将被拉进第一个船闸
by the tug trains
在拖车旁边
on each side of the canal
在运河的两边
the downstream gate will close
下游的闸门会关闭
water from upstream will be fed in to fill the lock
上游的水将被输入来填满水闸
the boat will float up
船会浮起来
then once the water level rises
那么一旦水位上升
to match that of the next lock
与下一个锁的匹配
the gate will open
大门就会打开
and the ship will be pulled into the next lock
船会被拉进下一个船闸
then the gates will close
然后大门就会关闭
the water level will rise again the gates will open
水位会再次上升，大门会打开
then this will all happen one more time
那么这一切都会再次发生
until the third lock
直到第三把锁
raises the ship to the water level of Gaddin Lake
把船抬到加丁湖的水位
those 85 feet or 26 meters above sea level
那些海拔85英尺或26米
believe it or not
信不信由你
it is these three lochs
就是这三个湖
exclusively that limit what size
专门限制什么尺寸
a large portion of the world's container ship fleet
世界上很大一部分集装箱船队
can be a ship has to be under 1200
可以是一艘船必须在1200以下
feet or 366 meters long
英尺或366米长
and 168 feet
和168英尺
or 51 meters wide to be accepted in the Panama Canal
或者51米宽才能被巴拿马运河接受
and so a huge proportion of the world ships are built
所以世界上很大一部分船只是建造的
to be exactly
确切地说
this size this class of ship is called Neo Panamax
这个尺寸这个级别的船叫做Neo Panamax
or New Panamax or Post Panamax
或新巴拿马型或后巴拿马型
depending on who you ask
取决于你问谁
of course
当然
there are certainly ships larger than the Neo Panamax
肯定有比新巴拿马号更大的船
size The Panama Canal has a size limit of about
尺寸巴拿马运河的尺寸限制约为
15000 TEU or 20 foot equivalent units
15000标准箱或20英尺当量单位
that's a measure of a ship's capacity
那是测量一艘船的载客量
based off how many of these
根据这些有多少
20 foot containers they could carry
他们可以携带20英尺长的集装箱
now the largest container ship in existence
现在最大的集装箱船
the OOCL Hong Kong has a capacity of over
东方海外香港有限公司的容量超过
21 000 TEU
21 000标准箱
this ship like many of those larger than 15000 TEU
这艘船和许多大于15000标准箱的船一样
exclusively keeps to the East Asia to Europe route
专营东亚至欧洲航线
as it can't
因为它不能
efficiently make trips that require transit
高效地进行需要过境的旅行
between the Pacific and Atlantic
在太平洋和大西洋之间
since it would have to circumvent
因为它必须规避
South America
南美洲
it was really not long ago
那真是不久前的事了
that the larger ships
大型船只
that could go through the Panama Canal
可以通过巴拿马运河
were far smaller than the current
远小于水流
15000 TEU size
1500标准箱尺寸
you see up until 2016
直到2016年
the Panama Canal could only fit ships smaller than
巴拿马运河只能容纳小于
5000 TEU
5000标准箱
that's because up until 2016 these didn't exist
那是因为直到2016年，这些都不存在。
The Panama Canal's new locks
巴拿马运河的新船闸
the old locks can only fit a ship
旧船闸只能装一艘船
106 feet or 32 meters wide
106英尺或32米宽
but still
但还是
given the enormous importance of this waterway
鉴于这条水道的重要性
ships were still then built
当时还在建造船只
specifically to fit through
专门为了适应
in fact 50 of the old blocks users
事实上50个旧块用户
were exactly as wide as this width limit
正好和这个宽度限制一样宽
suggesting they were likely built for exactly
表明它们很可能是为
that purpose
那个目的
this was a problem for the Panama Canal though
这对巴拿马运河来说是个问题
because believe it or not
因为信不信由你
the canal has competitors
运河有竞争对手
it all has to do with geography
这都和地理有关
when traveling from East Asia to the US East Coast
从东亚到美国东海岸旅行时
which is one of the busiest shipping routes
这是最繁忙的航线之一
in the world
在世界上
it really is not all that much further to go west
向西走真的不远
than East going from Hong Kong to New York for example
而不是从香港到纽约的东部
the distance heading west through the Indian Ocean
向西穿过印度洋的距离
Suez Canal Mediterranean and Atlantic
苏伊士运河地中海和大西洋
is only a few hundred miles or kilometers longer
只有几百英里或公里长
than going east across the Pacific
而不是向东横跨太平洋
and through the Panama Canal
通过巴拿马运河
meanwhile the Panama Canal is not cheap
同时巴拿马运河也不便宜
they charge a 90 dollar toll per 20 foot container
他们每20英尺集装箱收费90美元
meaning that most ships
这意味着大多数船只
carrying thousands of loaded containers
载着数千个装载的集装箱
pay hundreds of thousands of dollars
支付数十万美元
for just a single transit
只需一次运输
with the new locks and their higher capacity
有了新锁和更高的容量
single ships
单船
can possibly be assessed more than 1 million dollars
可能超过100万美元
per transit if they're the largest size fully loaded
如果它们是最大尺寸的满载，则每次运输
The Suez Canal meanwhile typically charges lower tolls
与此同时，苏伊士运河通常收取较低的通行费
a ship sailing that Hong Kong to New York route
从香港开往纽约的船
therefore
因此
might choose to take the slightly longer route
可能会选择稍微长一点的路线
via the Suez Canal
经由苏伊士运河
versus the Panama Canal
对巴拿马运河
as in the end when you consider the tolls
最终当你考虑通行费时
it might end up being less expensive
它最终可能会更便宜。
now both canals are constantly changing their fees
现在两条运河都在不断改变收费标准
in order to compete with the other
为了与对方竞争
but still throughout the past decade
但在过去的十年里
the Suez Canal seems to maintain a slight edge in cost
苏伊士运河的成本似乎略有上升
The Panama Canal's other competitor though is trains
巴拿马运河的另一个竞争者是火车
for the crucial East Asia to US East Coast route
重要的东亚至美国东海岸航线
going through the Panama Canal
通过巴拿马运河
while much faster than circumnavigating the continent
虽然比环游大陆快得多
is still not a direct route
仍然不是直接路线
on the Hong Kong to New York route
在香港到纽约的航线上
the Panama Canal represents an almost 3000
巴拿马运河代表着
mile or 5000 kilometer diversion from the alternative
一英里或五千公里的分流
crossing the US by land
陆路穿越美国
it is pretty standard practice to ship cargo from
这是相当标准的做法装运货物从
East Asia to Los Angeles
东亚到洛杉矶
and then load it up on trains to get it
然后装上火车去拿
to the US East Coast
到美国东海岸
while overall
虽然总体
this usually ends up a little more expensive
这通常会更贵一点。
than going through the Panama Canal
而不是通过巴拿马运河
it saves about a week in transit time
它节省了大约一周的运输时间
and for many shippers this is worth it
对于许多托运人来说，这是值得的
trains with their relatively low cost
成本相对较低的火车
represent a considerable competitor to the canal
代表着运河的一个相当大的竞争对手
and it is the competition with these
这是与这些的竞争
and the Suez Canal
还有苏伊士运河
that pushed the Panama Canal to make an expansion
推动巴拿马运河扩张
that's why they spent 5
这就是为什么他们花了5英镑。
4 billion dollars to build these bigger locks
40亿美元来造这些更大的锁
that could fit larger
那可能适合更大的
15000 TEU ships
15000标准箱船
this would let more of the world's shipping fleet
这将让世界上更多的船队
through
通过
and these bigger ships thanks to economies of scale
由于规模经济，这些更大的船
have lower cost per container
每个容器的成本较低
which helps make the canal more attractive
这有助于使运河更具吸引力
in comparison to its trains
与火车相比
or Suez's competition
或者苏伊士的竞争对手
now this expansion is a great example
现在这个扩展是一个很好的例子
of the butterfly effect
蝴蝶效应
in one instance
在一个例子中
because the Panama Canal
因为巴拿马运河
widened its size limit by a few dozen feet
把它的尺寸限制扩大了几十英尺
the state of New Jersey had to spend 1
新泽西州不得不花1美元
7 billion dollars to raise a bridge by a few dozen feet
70亿美元把桥抬高几十英尺
you see in order to get to much of the port of Newark
你看，为了到达纽瓦克的大部分港口
which is one of the largest and busiest in the U
这是美国最大、最繁忙的城市之一
S ships have to pass under the Bayonne Bridge
S船必须从巴约恩桥下通过
as a huge proportion of the shipping traffic to the US
占到美国海运的很大一部分
East Coast goes through the Panama Canal
东海岸穿过巴拿马运河
before the new set of locks
在新锁之前
many of the ships
许多船只
that wanted to use the port of Newark
想利用纽瓦克港
were the smaller size
是小一号的吗？
which could all fit under the Bayonne Bridge
这些都可以放在巴约恩桥下
sitting at 151 feet or
坐在151英尺或
46 meters above the water
水面以上46米
with the canal expansion project though
运河扩建工程
more ships would start making their way to New York
会有更多的船开往纽约
that would be too large
那就太大了
to fit under the Bayonne Bridge
以适应Bayonne大桥下
therefore
因此
in order for the port of New York to stay competitive
为了让纽约港保持竞争力
they just had to raise that bridge
他们只需要把桥架起来
beyond that all up and down the U
除此之外，美国上下都在
S East Coast
东海岸
from Miami to Savannah to Charleston
从迈阿密到萨凡纳再到查尔斯顿
to Baltimore and to New York
去巴尔的摩和纽约
ports quickly spent
港口迅速耗尽
millions and billions of dollars
几百万和几十亿美元
to build facilities that would fit the bigger ships
建造适合大型船只的设施
in time for the opening of the new canal locks
正好赶上新运河水闸的开通
still today though
不过今天还是
many ports on the East Coast
东海岸的许多港口
do not have the depth
没有深度
and facilities needed to handle these Neo
以及处理这些Neo所需的设施
Panamax ships
巴拿马船
this though presents an opportunity for the Caribbean
不过这也为加勒比海地区提供了一个机会
Deepwater ports in the Caribbean
加勒比海的深水港口
are developing themselves into major transshipment hubs
正在发展成为主要的转运中心
what these are
这些是什么
are ports where larger ships
是大型船只的港口
like the largest 15000 TEU
比如最大的15000标准箱
container ships that can now go through the canal
现在可以通过运河的集装箱船
will unload their cargo
会卸下他们的货物
which will then be loaded again onto smaller ships
然后将再次装载到较小的船上
bound for smaller ports
开往较小的港口
closer to the cargo's destination
更接近货物的目的地
up and now on the East Coast
现在在东海岸
huge amounts of foreign money
巨额外币
are flowing into the Caribbean
正流入加勒比海
to develop these transshipment hubs
发展这些转运枢纽
CMA CGM
达飞集团
a shipping company from France
一家来自法国的航运公司
that ranks as the world's third largest
是世界第三大
operates the port of Kingston Jamaica
经营牙买加金斯敦港
DP World from the UAE operates the port of Cayo Santo
来自阿联酋的DP World运营Cayo Santo港
in the Dominican Republic
在多米尼加共和国
meanwhile the port of Freeport
与此同时自由港港
in the Bahamas
在巴哈马群岛
is operated by Hutchison Port Holdings from Hong Kong
由和记港口控股在香港运营
all of these companies and more
所有这些公司等等
have
有
and continue to focus on expanding these Cuban ports
并继续集中精力扩建这些古巴港口
to suit the increased traffic
以适应增加的交通
making its way through the Panama Canal
穿过巴拿马运河
into the Cuban
进入古巴
and eventually to its destination on the East Coast
最终到达东海岸的目的地
sometime soon though
不过很快就会
something could happen
可能会发生一些事情
that would be simultaneously great for the Cuban ports
同时对古巴港口也有好处
but terrible for the Panama Canal
但对巴拿马运河来说很糟糕
you see two countries
你看到两个国家
to the north of Panama is Nicaragua
巴拿马北部是尼加拉瓜
by linking both the Atlantic and the Pacific
通过连接大西洋和太平洋
to the large Lake Nicaragua
到尼加拉瓜湖
one could have another connection between the oceans
海洋之间可能有另一种联系
there has been a long history of attempts
有很长的尝试历史
to build this canal
修建这条运河
most recently in the past decade
最近一次是在过去十年中
with a failed scheme by a Chinese billionaire
与一个中国亿万富翁的失败计划有关
given that this failure was recent
鉴于这次失败是最近的
there are no current construction plans
目前没有建设计划
but at least somewhere
但至少在某个地方
the world is going to need more canal capacity
世界需要更多的运河容量
between the Pacific and the Atlantic
在太平洋和大西洋之间
the shipping industry is growing
航运业正在增长
at a solid rate of about 5% annually
以每年约5%的稳定速度
and the Panama Canal can only expand so much
巴拿马运河只能扩张这么多
one issue is that the Panama Canal
一个问题是巴拿马运河
could literally run out of water
可能真的用完了水
you see each time the canal's locks open
每次运河的水闸打开
millions of gallons of water flow out and downstream
数百万加仑的水流向下游
usually this is not a problem
通常这不是问题
because the lake upstream has enough water
因为上游的湖泊有足够的水
but sometimes during periods of reduced rainfall
但有时在降雨量减少的时期
there just won't be enough water to both release
只是没有足够的水来释放
the amounts needed to operate the locks
操作锁所需的金额
and keep the lake at a deep enough level
保持湖水足够深
for the largest ships to transit
供最大的船只过境
at these times which included much of spring 2019
在这些时间，包括2019年春季的大部分时间
the canal will have to place restrictions
运河将不得不设置限制
on how much weight
重量是多少？
cargo ships can carry
货船可以携带
as this will affect how deep they sit in the water
因为这会影响它们在水中的深度
they've attempted to limit the effects of this
他们试图限制这种影响
by installing systems to recapture some of the water
通过安装系统来回收一些水
used to operate the locks
用来操作锁
and there are also
还有
potential plans to build an additional
建造附加设施的潜在计划
upstream dam to create an additional reservoir
上游大坝增建水库
but these problems are only expected to worsen
但这些问题预计只会恶化
as climate change
随着气候变化
exacerbates the severity of droughts in the region
加剧了该地区干旱的严重性
all told what happens in Panama affects the world
巴拿马发生的事影响了全世界
if a drought
如果干旱
in Panama restricts the throughput of the canal
在巴拿马限制了运河的吞吐量
the world economy will feel it
世界经济将会感受到
that's because
那是因为
shipping is what connects the world's economy
航运是连接世界经济的纽带
and the Panama Canal
还有巴拿马运河
is one of the most important connectors
是最重要的连接器之一
in shipping
在运输中
the canal effectively brings the economies on one side
运河有效地把经济带到了一边
closer to those on the other
更接近另一个
and so no matter what happens
所以无论发生什么
it will continue to serve as the world's shortcut
它将继续成为世界的捷径
now one of the things that
现在有一件事
those working at the Panama Canal
那些在巴拿马运河工作的人
need to understand
需要了解
is how water works
水是如何工作的
as in how weather works
就像天气如何运作一样
how the water cycle works how tides work
水循环如何运作，潮汐如何运作
all of these things are also though concepts that
所有这些东西也是概念